Now that our project is setup and ready
现在我们的项目已经配置好了
to go let's setup the player game object.
下面我们来配置玩家对象
First I'm going to make sure that I'm in the Scene view
首先确认自己在Scene视图
for the best view of the scene we are working with.
这个视图可以给让我们在场景中更好地工作
Next I'm going to add the player's ship model.
然后我将添加玩家的太空船模型
We can find the player ship in the Assets
船的模型在Assets文件夹
folder in the Models directory.
的Models目录下
Drag the vehicle_playerShip
将vehicle_playerShip
from the Models directory in to the Hierarchy view.
从Models目录拖拽到Hierarchy视窗
We can also drag this model directly in to the
我们也可以把这个模型直接
Scene view if we choose to.
拖拽到Scene视图中
Either way is correct.
以上两种方法都可以
Let's get a better view of the model in our scene.
让我把模型看的更清楚一点
To do this we want to focus, or frame the
我们想让Scene视图的相机
selected game object with the Scene view camera.
聚焦于游戏中的某个对象,或者让该对象占满整个Scene视图
We can do this by either choosing Edit - Frame Selected
我们可以点击Edit -> Frame Selected
or by using the hot-key F
或者使用热键F
while the pointer is in the Scene view.
如果指针在Scene视图中的时候
Double clicking on the game object in the Hierarchy view
我们也可以通过双击Hierarchy(层级)视图中的对象
will also focus the Scene view camera.
达到聚焦于某个游戏对象的目的.
There's our player ship.
这就是我们的玩家船只
Now that she's in the scene, let's rename her
我们来将场景中的玩家船只重命名
in the Hierarchy. Click on the game object in the hierarchy and
单击Hierarchy视图中的游戏对象
type either the Return or Enter key to enable editing.
然后敲击退格或者回车键编辑游戏对象的名称
We can also click on the game object
我们也可以通过缓慢单击这个对象
twice, slowly, to enable editing as well.
两次来启动对这个对象名称的编辑
Name the game object Player
把这个游戏对象命名为Player(玩家)
and then hit Enter or Return to confirm that change.
然后我们再敲击回车键确认名称
We want our player ship to be at origin.
我们希望玩家船只在原点
Origin is the centre of our 3 dimensional scene
原点时我们三维视图的中心
where the X, Y and Z coordinates are (0, 0, 0).
X, Y and Z 坐标是 (0, 0, 0)
Let's use the context sensitive gear menu
我们在Transform(变形) 插件
in the upper right of the Transform component
右上角的齿轮下拉菜单中
and select Reset.
选择Reset
This will reset the transform's position,
这个操作会将变换的位置,
rotation and scale.
旋转和缩放的信息重置
Now we have guaranteed that the model is
现在我们可以保证模型
placed perfectly at origin.
已经完美的放在原点了
We want this ship to fly around, fight enemies
我们希望敌我双方的飞船都可以飞
yet be vulnerable enough that we can be destroyed
我们可以驾驶玩家飞船轻松击落
if we're not careful as we pilot our ship.
敌方飞船
We currently have nothing more than a mesh model
我们现在仅仅只有一个
that represents the player in our scene.
在场景中展示玩家飞船的模型
The game object that holds our ship
飞船这个对象
has a number of components that define
由很多组件定义而成
what our ship is and where it is in the game.
例如飞船是什么样子,在游戏中的什么位置
The game object uses a mesh filter
游戏的对象使用网格过滤器组件
to hold our mesh model
保存我们的模型
and a mesh renderer to render the ship
使用网格渲染组件在场景中
in our scene.
渲染飞船
The renderer references 2 materials,
渲染组件引用了2个材质
shown here at the bottom for our convenience.
他们都在渲染组件的下方,便于我们查看
The game object uses the information in
游戏对象在
the transform component to know where the
变形插件负责记录模型的位置
model is in the game, what direction it is facing
模型的方向
and what scale it currently is.
模型的缩放信息
To set up our player game object we will
现在我们来设置我们自己的游戏对象
be adding more components that perform
我们需要在此基础上增加更多的组建
specialised functions, and we will be creating
自定义功能，使用简单的脚本
our own components using simple scripting.
来增加我们自定义组件
We will be moving our ship using physics,
我们将在飞船的移动中应用物理法则(这里指移动中的倾斜)
though with an arcade style
街机风格中也是这样应用的
and we need physics to detect our collisions
同时我们也需要检测场景中
between the player and other game objects
玩家和其他对象之间的
in the scene.
物理碰撞
To use physics we need to add a rigid body component.
我们需要增加刚体组件来使用物理法则
I'm going to quickly reduce the view of these
先点击标题栏
referenced materials by clicking on
将材质栏信息简化
the header bars so that it's easier to
这样我们不使用滚动条也能轻松找到
see and access the Add Component
Add Component
button without scrolling.
按键
Now let's click on Add Component
现在点击 Add Component
and select Physics - Rigid Body.
选择Physics -> Rigid Body
This attaches a rigid body component
为当前游戏对象
to our game object.
增加一个刚体组件
By default the rigid body assumes
刚体默认我们
we want to use gravity, and well, we're in space
使用重力，但是这是在太空，
and we don't want to fall out of the game
我可不想让掉到游戏外面去
so let's deselect Use Gravity.
所以让我们把Use Gravity的前面的钩选去掉
With the rigid body attached our game object
我们的游戏对象已经增加了刚体组件
now uses the built in physics engine.
现在我们可以使用内置的物理引擎了
To detect collisions the physics engine
为了使用物理引擎检测
through the rigid body, needs to know the
刚体对象的碰撞
volume of our objects.
我们需要知道对象的大小
We need to know how much space these objects
我们需要知道这个对象在空间中所占的体积
take up in our game to calculate the collisions.
来计算游戏中发生的碰撞
We give this information to the rigid body by
我们使用一个笼子包住我们的游戏对象
using a cage that we wrap around our game objects.
把这个笼子的信息作为刚体信息的一部分
This cage defines the volume of that object.
这个笼子定义了物体的大小
The cage is called a Collider.
这个笼子叫做Collider(碰撞检测机)
Let's use the Add Component button again.
让我们再用一次Add Component按钮
This time select Physics - Capsule Collider.
这次我们选择 Physics -> Capsule Collider(胶囊碰撞检测机)
This puts a simple cage around our player game object.
这会将我们的玩家对象套上个简单的笼子
This looks like a sphere but that's because
它看起来像个球,没错
a capsule collider is defined by 2 spheres
因为胶囊形状的碰撞检测机是由2个球体
and the space in between them,
和球体之间的空间一起定义的
and we are seeing both spheres in the same place.
现在的情况是两个球面重合在了一起
Let's change the capsule collider's size.
现在改变下胶囊碰撞检测机的形状
The default orientation for a capsule collider
默认的胶囊碰撞检测机的方向是
is up and down or along the Y axis.
沿Y轴上下方向上的
This is to fit a humanoid object.
这是为了适应类似人形的对象
Our ship is longest along the Z axis
我们的飞船在Z的方向上最长
so let's change the direction to Z
所以我们将碰撞检测机的方向调整为沿Z轴
and reduce the radius and increase the height.
然后减小半径并增加长度
For a better view let's change our orientation.
为了看的更清楚,我们改变下视角方向
For a top-down view let's click on the
我们想自上而下的看
Scene view gizmo and click on the Y arm.
我们点击Scene视图右上角的小图标上的Y
In this view it's easier to fine tune the shape.
这个视角让我们更容易调整好形状
We simply need to choose the values
我们只需要选择碰撞检测机
for radius and height that comfortably fit
的长度和半径使其刚好
the collider to our model.
套住我们的模型
Now for the purposes of this game,
对于当前这个游戏而言
which is fairly simple, the capsule collider is sufficient.
简单的胶囊碰撞检测机已经足够用了
There are other alternatives however.
当然还有很多种其它的碰撞检测机
Let's click on the Add Component button again
让我们再点击一次Add Component按钮.
and select Physics.
选择Physics
There is the Box Collider and Sphere Collider as well.
这里有Box Collider(盒子形状碰撞检测机)和Sphere Collider(球形碰撞检测机)
The box collider and sphere colliders are
上述两种碰撞检测机
2 other primitive colliders like the
与胶囊形碰撞检测机一样都是
capsule collider, but there is a more complex
最简单的原始碰撞检测机,还有一种复杂的碰撞检测机
collider called a Mesh Collider
叫做Mesh Collider(网格碰撞检测机)
where we can supply the collision mesh ourselves.
我们可以自己提供碰撞网格模型
For more information see the documentation
更多信息请参阅碰撞检测机相关
on colliders and the lesson on
文档或者参阅下方连接的
colliders linked below.
碰撞检测机课程
At this point I think it's important to note
必须强调
that the primitive colliders, the box,
盒形,球形,胶囊形这些原始碰撞检测机的效率
sphere and capsule are far more performant
要远比网格碰撞检测机高
and should be used whenever possible
因此，如果可能，请尽量使用
over the mesh collider.
简单的碰撞检测机
For more information please see the
更详细信息
Compound Colliders section of the
请参阅Rigid Body文档的
Rigid Body documentation linked below.
Compound Colliders章节
If however we have a more complex shape that
如果形状复杂
can't be accommodated by any of the primitive colliders
所有的原始碰撞检测机都不适用
and for some reason doesn't work by using
复合碰撞检测机也不能很好工作
a compound collider we can select Mesh Collider.
这时我们才会使用网格碰撞检测机
Let's look at the mesh collider in action.
我们来动手建立个网格碰撞检测机
Select Mesh Collider and yes,
选择Mesh Collider和Replace
replace the existing component.
替换当前存在的组件
This will remove the capsule collider and
胶囊碰撞检测机将会被
use the mesh collider instead.
网格碰撞检测机取代
To have a better look at the mesh collider
为了更清楚地查看网格碰撞检测机
let's turn off the mesh renderer.
我们先关闭网格渲染
This reveals the green lines of the mesh collider
我们可以看到本来被网格渲染隐藏了的
that were hidden underneath the rendered mesh.
网格碰撞检测机的绿线
We can see how complex this cage is.
这个图形非常复杂
Unity must check the position of each
Unity在做碰撞检测
triangle in the cage relative to
的时候会计算这个图形上面的
the other colliders in the scene
每一个三角形是否与
to properly detect a collision.
其它对象发生碰撞
If for whatever reason we use a mesh collider
如果我们选择使用网格碰撞检测机
rather than a primitive collider
而非使用简单的原始碰撞检测机
it is best that we use a simplified mesh.
最好先将网格碰撞检测机简化
The mesh collider holds a reference to the
在网格碰撞检测机插件中
mesh it's using in the Mesh slot
有个Mesh栏引用了当前对象的
on the component.
网格模型
By default Unity will use the mesh
默认情况下Unity会在网格碰撞检测机中
in the mesh filter if one is present.
使用网格过滤器组建中存在的网格模型
We can simply swap this out with a new
我们找一个简化了的网格模型
simplified mesh of our choice.
来替换一下
We have supplied a simplified mesh in the Models directory.
我们已经在Models目录下准备好了一个简化后的网格模型
Open the Model file and select the Mesh asset.
打开Model文件夹选择这个网格模型
Drag the Mesh asset in to the Mesh slot
将模型拖到网格碰撞检测机的
on the mesh collider.
Mesh栏
Now we can see the substantially simplified
我们看到,网格碰撞检测机的模型
mesh being used as the collider.
已经被简化了
Let's turn the mesh renderer back on.
我们把网格渲染再打开
For the purposes of this game we could use a
本游戏使用胶囊碰撞机已经足够了
capsule collider, but this game will be
但这个游戏很简单
simple enough to absorb the larger cost
所以即使使用了网格碰撞检测机
of the mesh collider, so let's leave it as it is.
而过多消耗的资源对游戏的影响也不大,我们先留着网格碰撞检测机继续使用
Now that we have a working collider,
现在我们已经有了碰撞检测机
we need to adjust the collider's settings.
我们需要对它作些设定
For this game we don't need to
对当前这个游戏来说
or want to detect full physics collisions.
我们不需要检测完整的物理碰撞
We simply need our collisions to trigger an action.
碰撞对我们来说只不过是一个触发器
So select Is Trigger,
所以钩选Is Trigger(对于Unity5 而言Convex 也必须钩选)
making this a Trigger Collider.
这样我们的对象就是一个碰撞触发器
Lastly, let's add a little sizzle to our ship.
最后给我们飞船加点喷射效果
In Prefabs - VFX - Engines
在Prefabs - VFX - Engines
there is an engines_player prefab.
有个engines_player 预制件
Let's add this to the player ship.
把它加到玩家飞船上
Drag the prefab on to the player ship
将预制件拖到Hierarchy视图中的
in the Hierarchy to add it as a
玩家飞船上
child game object.
让它成为一个子对象
The Engines prefab consists of 2 particle systems.
这个引擎喷射的预制件有2个部分
Now they look funny in the Scene view,
现在在场景视图中看起来有点滑稽
as the particles are billboarding
因为无论从哪个角度看引擎喷射总是
or facing to the camera at all times.
一直竖直的对着相机
If however we are in top-down mode
当我们从上往下看的时候
like our game will be they look just fine.
这个引擎喷射的位置似乎刚刚好
If the gizmos in the scene are too large
如果我们觉得这个白色的小齿轮图标太大了
we can reduce them by selecting the gizmos
我们可以通过点选场景视图工具栏里面的gizmos
button in the Scene view toolbar
中的滑动栏
and adjusting the slider.
将它缩小
Now our player ship is setup.
我们的玩家飞船也已经设定好了
In the next assignment we will setup the
下一个任务是设置
camera and the lights.
相机位置和光